Care to explain yourself, Dr. Takashina?
你要解釋一下嗎，高階？
The paper on the success of the Snipe surgery
“醫狙”手術成功的論文
should be here as the headlining article.
應該要刊在封面才對
I don't see a single article regarding the Snipe
但是我卻連一篇相關的論文
published in here.
都沒有看到
You've completed only two Snipe surgery cases at Tojo University Hospital,
你在東城大學只完成兩個案例
and the results have been less than satisfying.
而且結果都不盡人意
I'm very sorry.
我很抱歉
There isn't much time left until the election for Chairman.
外科學會的理事長選舉就快到了
What I need is Impact Factor, you know?
我需要影響因子，你知道嗎？
Impact. Factor.
影響因子
If you can't get me results next time,
如果下次還拿不出成果
the Snipe will be out of your hands completely.
你就休想再碰“醫狙”了！
If you wish to stay in this business,
如果你還想留在醫療界
bring me some results.
就拿出點成績來
After two Snipe surgery failures, Dr. Takashina had few chances left,
經歷兩次失敗的手術 高階醫生的機會所剩無幾
and the pressure was on.
他面對很大的壓力
And as no schedule was set for the Snipe's next use,
但下一台“醫狙”手術卻遙遙無期
he couldn't redeem himself.
他無法力挽狂瀾
It seems there hasn't been another Snipe surgery since last time.
繼上次之後 就沒有安排新的“醫狙”手術
There's someone I would like to introduce to you.
我想介紹一個人給你認識
As the number of patients hoping for Dr. Saeki's care rose,
隨著來尋求佐伯醫師幫助的病患增加
there wasn't a day he didn't operate.
他天天都必須動手術
And I got to be caretaker of two new patients.
我也必須照顧兩位新病患
The first, scheduled for operation by Dr. Saeki,
第一位是患有二尖瓣狹窄症
is Mr. Hideo Kusunoki, suffering from mitral stenosis.
準備接受佐伯式手術的楠木秀雄先生
Dr. Tokai will be looking after you until the operation.
手術之前，渡海醫生會照顧你
-Nice to meet you.
-拜託您了
And my second patient
第二位病患
was brought in by the clinical trial coordinator, Kinoshita.
是協調員木下小姐帶來的
Hayato Tamura, a music student.
音樂大學的學生田村隼人
He was diagnosed with mitral insufficiency
他被診斷出患有二尖瓣關閉不全症
and he's volunteered for an emergency Snipe surgery,
為了能趕上將在美國舉辦的鋼琴大賽
hoping to recover in time for a piano contest in America.
他自願接受“醫狙”緊急手術
The important thing to note is his father.
要特別注意的是他的父親
If it isn't Mr. Tamura!
田村先生，歡迎歡迎
A candidate for Vice Minister of the Ministry of Health, Koji Tamura.
厚生勞動省 下一任事務次官候選人田村浩司
If there are no problems in the test, we can operate right away.
如果檢查後沒問題，就能立刻動手術
You can leave the hospital about a week after we finish.
術後一週，您就能出院了
Thank you.
那就拜託了
That Snipe tool is really something.
“醫狙”這個工具還真是了不起
The surgery that would save Dr. Takashina's career was decided
能拯救高階醫生職涯的手術終於排定
and the preparation was soon underway.
術前檢查也立刻開始進行
-Dr. Sera. Bring me a towel, would you? -Okay.
-世良，能幫我拿毛巾嗎？ -好
What are you doing? Watch out!
你在幹嘛？小心點！
Sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me.
不好意思
Dr. Takashina seems to be on edge lately.
高階醫生最近似乎都緊張兮兮
This is the first Snipe surgery in a while after all.
畢竟這是等了很久的“醫狙”手術
Excuse me.
打擾了
These are Hayato's lab results and echocardiogram.
這是隼人的血液檢查 和心臟超音波檢查結果
The MRI results will be in tomorrow.
明天會做核磁共振檢查
-Here you go. -Thank you.
-請您過目 -謝謝
Sorry for getting angry with you earlier.
抱歉剛剛對你發脾氣
It's all right. I'm sorry.
沒事，我才覺得抱歉
Are you still working?
您還不回家嗎？
Given last time's issues,
根據上次出現的問題
I have to make many revisions to my paper.
我必須大幅修改我的論文
-Anything else? -No, sorry.
-還有事嗎？ -沒有，抱歉
Dr. Tokai never writes papers.
渡海醫生從不寫論文
This is new to me.
我覺得很新奇
It's not enough to just write a paper.
光寫論文是不夠的
What matters is where it's published.
重點是發表在哪個學術期刊上
Impact Factor, right?
影響因子，對吧？
The most influential Japanese publication,
日本醫界最有影響力的
The Japan Surgical Journal, has an Impact Factor of seven.
《日本外科期刊》的影響因子是七
Ten years ago, when Dr. Saeki first performed the Saeki Method,
十年前，佐伯教授 第一次發表佐伯式手術時
it was first published here.
論文就刊登在這裡
And because of that,
因此
Dr. Saeki became famous overnight.
佐伯教授一夜成名
Since then, the doctor has published many articles
在那之後，佐伯教授 繼續發表了許多相關論文
sending his Impact Factor to 77.
影響因子總計有77
While Dr. Nishizaki's various papers are also widely published,
另一方面，西崎教授 發表了各種領域的論文
but his Impact Factor sits at 71.
但他的影響因子只有71
In other words, despite his efforts,
也就是說，雖然他很努力
Dr. Nishizaki's vast research isn't enough to compete.
但佐伯式手術相關論文的影響因子
Only the paper on the Saeki Method puts Dr. Saeki ahead.
就勝過了以研究為主的西崎教授
Tojo, an unknown hospital,
默默無名的東城大學
became an authority on cardiovascular surgery
瞬間成為心臟外科的權威
and patients from all over the world now gather here in Sakuranomiya City
以至於現在有來自全球的患者 都聚集到櫻宮市
to visit a local hospital.
這間地方醫院
A single paper's Impact Factor
一篇論文的影響因子
changed the world completely.
就徹底改變了全世界
If I can complete the Snipe paper,
要是我能完成“醫狙”的論文
I'll be able to overtake Dr. Saeki's Impact Factor.
就能超過佐伯教授的影響因子
And I'll do anything to achieve that.
我願意為此做任何事
But I still don't have enough real-world cases to complete the paper.
但完成論文所需的病例現在還不夠
I have to ensure the next one succeeds
我必須確保下一場手術的成功
to garner trust.
才能一口氣增加案例
By using the Snipe, we can save more lives.
使用“醫狙”，我們能拯救更多人命
Could you let me help you?
你願意讓我幫助你嗎？
If the Snipe is put into regular use,
如果“醫狙”變得普及
we'll be able to save lives around the world, as you said.
就像你說的 我們就能夠拯救世界各地的人
I think that's a wonderful goal.
我覺得這是個很了不起的目標
Sorry. I've said too much.
抱歉，我多嘴了
Excuse me.
那我先告辭
Dr. Sera.
世良
Yes?
是？
Could you gather data for me?
能請你幫我篩選
It would be helpful.
必要的數據嗎？
Yes. Of course.
當然可以
However, the next day, a critical problem was found…
但是第二天，田村隼人的檢查結果…
Dr. Takashina!
高階醫生
…in Hayato Tamura's test.
…就發現了大問題
What is this?
這是什麼？
It has come to light that Hayato is afflicted by cardiomyopathy
我們發現隼人患有肥厚性心肌症
and his heart has an unusual ventricular structure, winding and complex
心室內部結構與正常的心臟不同
like a vast jungle.
跟叢林一樣複雜
MITRAL VALVE - HYPERTROPHY
（二尖瓣、心肌肥大）
This will make it difficult to apply stitches
這種情況下，要在心跳之間的空檔
between heartbeats and reach the mitral valve.
到達二尖瓣會非常困難
A slight mistake could induce arrhythmia
只要稍微碰到心肌 就會引起心律不整
and kill the patient.
可能導致患者死亡
This is an extremely rare case requiring delicate care.
這是非常罕見的病例 需要細心的操作
Performing Snipe surgery on this patient--
在這位患者身上 使用“醫狙”動手術…
Are you trying to say you can't do it?
你是想說你辦不到吧？
Can you?
辦得到嗎？
It's impossible.
那是不可能的
Dr. Takashina, you finally had a chance!
高階醫生，你難得有這個機會
It cannot be done.
辦不到的事情就是辦不到
We'll have someone else operate.
那換成別人主刀吧
Enter.
進來
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
Dr. Tokai, you'll handle the Snipe surgery for us,
渡海，這次由你主刀“醫狙”的手術
won't you?
可以吧？
As you say, sir.
悉聽尊便
Dr. Tokai is taking on a Snipe surgery?
竟然是由渡海醫生 接手“醫狙”的手術？
How is this going to end?
事情會有什麼樣的發展？
Please wait.
請稍等
I know Dr. Tokai is a skilled surgeon,
我知道渡海醫生的技術很好
but entrusting him with Snipe surgery?
但您要將“醫狙”的手術交給他嗎？
It's a delicate operation requiring a steady hand.
這台手術需要像穿針引線那樣 精準細膩的技術
I can't think of anyone better for the job.
我覺得沒有比渡海更合適的人選了
If you're unsure, our only other option is to call it off.
你如果擔心，那就只能放棄手術了
I wonder what Dr. Nishizaki would say about that?
要是西崎教授知道了 不知道會怎麼說？
You can act as Dr. Tokai's assistant.
你可以當渡海的助手
Dr. Tokai as the starting surgeon?
一開始就讓渡海醫生主刀？
-That's a first. -I guess it is.
-這是第一次 -大概吧
He's usually there as assistant.
他通常都只當助手
-I wonder how it will turn out. -Me too.
-真好奇會怎樣 -就是說啊
Here's the Snipe's user manual.
這是“醫狙”的操作手冊
Stick it in the mitral valve and pull the switch, right?
插到二尖瓣，然後按下開關，對吧？
You'll need to take a complicated route this time.
這次需要從比較複雜的路徑下手
It will require practice.
需要模擬練習
I know a guy who practiced and practiced and he still failed.
我知道有人 模擬練習了幾百次還是失敗
Then, it's a waste of time.
那簡直是浪費時間
Without ever laying a finger on the Snipe,
渡海先生一次都沒碰過“醫狙”
the day of Dr. Tokai's operation arrived.
就到了手術當天
We'll now begin mitral valve replacement surgery with the Snipe.
現在開始進行 使用“醫狙”的二尖瓣置換手術
Scalpel.
手術刀
What is wrong?
怎麼了？
I don't have the faintest idea…
我一點頭緒都沒有
Dr. Tokai, what's wrong?
渡海醫生，怎麼了？
-I'm done. -What?
-我不做了 -什麼？
You're done?
你不做了？
Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生？
What does this mean?
這是怎麼一回事？
Well, I don't even… Mr. Kurosaki!
我也不清楚，黑崎
Let me check. I'll be right back.
是，我立刻去確認
What do you mean you're done?
為什麼不做了？
That's what I've decided as operating surgeon.
這就是身為主刀的我所做的決定
Explain yourself.
請解釋清楚
Both Hayato and we have been preparing for this.
隼人先生和我們都做足了準備
You're not prepared.
你才沒有做足準備
Did even pay attention to the apical papillary muscles?
你到底有沒有仔細看心尖的肌肉？
The apical papillary muscles…
心尖的肌肉…
There's nothing we can do.
那也沒辦法了
It was his decision.
這要由主刀決定
-But… -The operating surgeon
-可是… -主刀醫生
is Dr. Tokai.
是渡海
Get a test on the heart muscles.
檢查一下病患的心肌
-No changes in condition? -Right.
-狀況沒有異常？ -好的
A surprising discovery was made upon further examination.
進一步檢查之後，有了驚人的發現
The apical papillary muscles much weaker than usual.
他的心尖肌肉比正常情況還要弱很多
We won't be able to insert the Snipe as usual.
這樣就無法像正常一樣插入“醫狙”
If we had tried back there,
要是當時這麼做
the apex would have torn,
心尖就會被撕裂
causing hemorrhaging.
導致大出血
Seeing such subtle heart movements…
光是從細微的心臟跳動
How did he notice that?
他就看出來了？
What are you talking about? You cannot cancel the surgery.
你在說什麼？不能取消手術
Allow Dr. Tokai to carry out the operation.
繼續叫那個渡海開刀
If it succeeds, it will be the case we need for the Snipe.
如果成功 會成為“醫狙”很寶貴的案例
And it will save this paper.
也能提升論文的品質
But if we fail…
但要是失敗…
If you fail,
如果失敗
we make sure Tojo University takes responsibility for it.
全部推給東城大學就好
Oh, right.
對了
The text is a bit small.
字體有點小
And use a Gothic font.
還有，換成哥德體
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Is it really possible to operate on Hayato
用“醫狙”來替隼人先生動手術
using the Snipe?
真的可以嗎？
Of course, it is.
當然可以
But to do so,
但如果要成功
we'll have to reach the mitral valve without damaging the ventricle.
就得在不傷及心室內部的情況下 抵達二尖瓣
We have to find a new route.
我們得找到新的路徑
Will you help me?
你願意幫我嗎？
Yes.
我願意
We'll make an exact replica of Hayato's heart with a 3D printer.
我們用3D列印機 完全重現隼人先生的心臟
Amazing!
好厲害
Incredible.
太厲害了
-It's just like the real thing. -Yes.
-簡直跟真的一樣 -是啊
Let's work around the apex and find a new way in.
我們避開心尖，找出新的路徑
Understood.
好的
Introducing Mr. Tamura, the next Vice Minister…
介紹下一任事務次官田村先生過來…
It would appear you're quite the fan of Dr. Nishizaki and Dr. Takashina.
看來你很喜歡西崎教授和高階醫生
A fan, you say?
這樣算喜歡嗎？
Am I wrong?
難道不是嗎？
I'm a fan of the elite. That's all.
我只是喜歡一流的東西而已
That's why I like Dr. Nishizaki, and you as well.
所以佐伯教授和西崎教授
A fan, as you say.
我都喜歡
I may be out of line asking this,
我這麼問可能不合適
but why, Dr. Saeki?
但是佐伯醫生
Why did you approve of taking in Mr. Tamura?
您為何會答應 接受田村先生的手術要求呢？
On top of that, you appointed Dr. Tokai as lead surgeon…
而且還指定渡海醫生擔任主刀
It would almost appear as if you are taking a liking to the Snipe.
看起來您好像滿喜歡醫狙的
It's all for the sake of the patients.
一切都是為了患者
It's no use.
還是不行
Let's try 11 millimeters.
試試看11毫米的
-From a 75-degree angle. -Right.
-從75度插入 -好
We continued our research on a new route for the Snipe.
我們繼續研究“醫狙”的新路徑
Finding an insertion point by the millimeter away from the apex,
插入點從心尖的地方，以毫米為單位
calculating the angle based on heartbeats.
並根據心跳來計算角度
We tried countless times.
我們試了無數次
They're still at it?
他們還在試啊？
Why the hell is Sera helping out with Teika's research?
世良幹嘛幫帝華大學做研究？
Finally,
終於
-We finally found a route. -Finally.
-找到了路徑 -終於找到了
Now, we'll be able to use the Snipe.
現在“醫狙”就能派上用場了
There's only one thing left that we can't anticipate.
這次手術只剩下一件無法預料的事
The surgeon.
主刀醫生
You called?
有什麼事嗎？
There isn't much time until the competition.
比賽馬上就要到了
We would like to operate as soon as tomorrow.
我們希望盡快動手術，明天也可以
When do you think it will be?
您預計什麼時候可以呢？
If that's the case, then we'll hurry. Right, Dr. Tokai?
這樣的話，我們會盡快 是吧，渡海醫生？
Before we do that, I have to ask.
在那之前，我想先問
Do you understand the Snipe surgery?
你們了解“醫狙”手術嗎？
-What? -Of course, they do.
-什麼？ -那是當然的
I explained it myself.
我已經說明過了
It has been performed twice at our hospital.
本院進行過兩次“醫狙”手術
The first time, the patient's splenic artery tore.
第一次，患者經歷脾動脈破裂
She almost died.
差點死亡
The second, the patient nearly bled to death due to human error.
第二次，由於主刀醫生的失誤 患者差點因為失血過多而死
Bled to death?
失血過多而死？
That's the surgery you'll be undergoing.
你要接受的就是這樣的手術
As they say, "Third time's the charm."
不過有人說“事不過三”
There's a chance of success, however…
手術可能會成功，但是
They also say, "History repeats itself."
也有人說“有二就有三”
Think it over.
好好考慮
-They had issues twice… -What is this about?
-竟然有過兩次事故… -這是怎麼一回事？
We'll explain it again shortly.
我待會再向您說明
What is this, Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生，你到底在想什麼？
-I just told them the truth. -No.
-我只是說實話而已 -才不是
You threatened them, by the way you said it.
你說話的方式分明就是威脅
What will we do if they opt out?
如果患者取消手術要怎麼辦？
We'll cancel the operation.
那就取消啊
Like we said, it's either going to be you or me who leaves.
就像我們之前說的 離職的不是你，就是我
If nobody undergoes Snipe surgery,
如果沒有人要做“醫狙”手術
I will be kicked out of here.
我就會被趕出這裡
Is that your goal?
那就是你的目的嗎？
To be quite frank, I don't like the idea of you operating.
老實說，我根本不想讓你主刀
But as a team, we must cooperate.
但身為團隊，我們就必須合作
Let's quit this bickering.
我們就別再互扯後腿了吧
This is the new Snipe route we've come up with for Hayato's surgery.
我們為了隼人先生的手術 找出了“醫狙”的新路徑
We'll be able to put this in the paper.
這也能寫進論文裡
We'll follow this route for the Snipe during the next operation.
下次手術請照這個路徑插入“醫狙”
HAYATO TAMURA NEW SNIPE ROUTE
（田村隼人的手術路徑）
RECYCLE BIN
（資源回收筒）
Wait, Dr. Tokai!
等一下，渡海醫生
What did you just do?
你剛做了什麼？
I trashed it.
刪掉了
Don't mess with me!
開什麼玩笑！
Do you understand your job?
你知道自己在做什麼嗎？
Dr. Takashina, stop. Please.
高階醫生，不要這樣
Please.
拜託你
We don't need it.
不需要那種東西
I've already decided on a route.
我已經決定好路徑了
I'll insert the Snipe 28 millimeters to the left from the apex.
我會從心尖往左28毫米的位置
Approaching from an 83-degree angle,
以83度的角度插入“醫狙”
reaching the mitral valve without damaging the left ventricle.
就能在不傷及左心室的情況下 到達二尖瓣
In fact, there is no other way.
也就是說，除此之外沒有別的可能
You have any problems with that?
你有什麼意見嗎？
If papers could save people, we wouldn't need doctors.
如果論文就能救人，那未免太簡單了
I do have a problem.
我確實有個問題
My pride as a doctor.
我身為醫生的驕傲
An unpublished doctor wouldn't understand.
不寫論文的醫生是不會懂的
You wouldn't know how much time and effort we put into it.
你不知道我們付出了多少時間和心力
If you had ever participated in research, you would understand what you've done.
如果你參加過研究 就會知道你剛做的事情有多過分
Papers are everything to us.
論文就是醫生的全部
I recognize you're a skilled surgeon.
我承認你的技術高超
But without all the thought that goes into it,
但是你不懂我們付出的心血
you're not a real doctor to me.
對我來說，你算不上真正的醫生
You're just a lowly craftsman.
充其量只是個手術職人罷了
You're giving me such praise.
你這樣誇獎我
You'll make me blush.
我會害羞的
We don't need it. I've already decided on a route.
不需要那種東西 我已經決定好路徑了
NEW SNIPE ROUTE
（手術路線）
I'll insert the Snipe 28 millimeters to the left from the apex.
我會從心尖往左28毫米的位置
Approaching from an 83-degree angle,
以83度的角度插入“醫狙”
reaching the mitral valve without damaging the left ventricle.
就能在不傷及左心室的情況下 到達二尖瓣
In fact, there is no other way.
也就是說，除此之外沒有別的可能
We have worked so hard to discover a new route,
我和高階醫生這麼努力找出新路徑
but Dr. Tokai was able to do it easily.
渡海醫生卻不費吹灰之力就辦到
What is this about, Dr. Nishizaki?
這是什麼意思，西崎教授？
We asked for urgent care.
我們希望能盡快治好他的病
If there is a chance of death, we want to use the Saeki Method.
但如果有死亡風險 我們還是進行佐伯式手術吧
That Dr. Tokai
那個叫渡海的人
may have said something misleading,
好像說了讓您誤會的話
but there is no problem.
手術沒有問題的
I've entrusted my trusted colleague, Dr. Takashina, to explain everything.
我最信任的高階醫生會向您說明
Thanks to Dr. Takashina's ardent persuasion,
在高階醫生的極力說服下
Mr. Tamura once again agreed on the Snipe surgery.
田村先生再次答應接受“醫狙”手術
Please read these documents.
請您閱讀這份資料
Mr. Tamura has requested that Hayato's operation
田村先生希望能在本週日
be performed this Sunday.
為隼人先生進行手術
Dr. Saeki will be away on business that day.
佐伯醫生那天要出差，不會在醫院
It's a direct request from the next Vice Minister of the Ministry of Health.
這可是下一任事務次官直接要求的
It's all the same to me.
對我來說沒差
That schedule works for me.
我當然也可以
Then it has been decided.
那就這麼決定了
Thank you for your time.
拜託各位了
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
You have a great responsibility.
你背負很大的責任
What do you mean?
你是什麼意思？
Dr. Nishizaki sees the Snipe as a simple tool to win him the election.
西崎教授只是把“醫狙” 當成贏得理事長選舉的工具
Aren't you tired of him always pestering you
他一直逼你拿出論文結果
for results for your paper?
你難道不覺得煩嗎？
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
I would like to offer you an official position here.
你要不要正式來我們醫院任職？
You can continue your research and testing on the Snipe as much as you would like
你可以在東城大學這裡 繼續進行“醫狙”的手術及研究
here at Tojo University.
直到你滿意為止
But this is Dr. Nishizaki's research.
但這是西崎教授的研究
No, it's yours.
不，這是你的研究
I want to support your research.
我想支持你的研究
The Snipe currently still requires a skilled surgeon.
“醫狙”目前仍需要 由醫術精湛的醫生操作
Our hospital will help bring it to life.
只有東城大學能賦予它生命
Are you trying to poach me along with the Snipe?
您是想將我和“醫狙” 都挖角過來嗎？
The name written at the end of your paper.
你論文結尾寫下的名字
That name represents the head of the research done.
代表這項研究的第一負責人
All you need to do, is write my name there.
你只要在那裡寫我的名字就好
Are you telling me to…
您是要我捨棄…
cut off Dr. Nishizaki?
西崎教授？
We can change the rules, if necessary.
如果有必要，可以改變規則
Wasn't it you who said that?
那不是你的座右銘嗎？
We're friends, not enemies.
我們是朋友，不是敵人
Meanwhile, preparations for Mr. Kusunoki's surgery next week
與此同時，佐伯醫生下週 將為楠木先生動的手術
were progressing steadily.
也正穩定地準備中
Okay, we're done.
好，可以了
I feel so lucky to receive your care, Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生親自來為我檢查
I'm extremely grateful.
我真是太榮幸了
I thought of checking on your condition before my trip to Tokyo tomorrow.
我明天要去東京出差 所以想先來看看您的狀況
Thank you so much.
真是太謝謝您了
Just in case, we'll take a coronary angiogram next Monday.
以防萬一，下週一 做個冠狀動脈血管造影吧
Okay.
好的
-Put it in the order. -Yes.
-先去安排 -好
I would like to offer you an official position here.
高階醫生 你要不要正式來我們醫院任職？
All you need to do, is write my name there.
你只要在那裡寫我的名字就好
The fateful day finally arrived.
命運般的一天終於到來
Excuse me. It's about Mr. Kusunoki.
不好意思，醫生 我要報告楠木先生的狀況
I scheduled a coronary angiogram.
我安排了冠狀動脈血管造影
-Orders from the professor? -Yes.
-教授的指示嗎？ -對
He told me to hurry, so I've set it for Monday.
他叫我盡快，我排了週一
-We'll do it after this. -What?
-等一下就做 -等一下？
Yes. Make preparations.
對，去準備
Wait. I'm not sure I can on such short notice…
等等，這麼突然，我不確定能…
Come in.
請進
As expected from you, Mr. Ikenaga, as editor-in-chief.
不愧是德高望重的池永主編
Me? I haven't done a thing.
不，這不是我的功勞
My predecessor did all the real work.
這都要多虧 能力非凡的前任主編打下基礎
All of the Journal's current editors were selected
我們期刊目前的所有編輯
by the former editor-in-chief.
都是前任主編決定的
He's expected to make an appearance today.
他今天也預計會出席
I'll introduce him shortly.
我待會再介紹你們認識
Enjoy yourselves.
請
It was almost time for a second try on Hayato Tamura's Snipe surgery.
終於要進行田村隼人的 第二次“醫狙”手術了
We'll now perform mitral valve replacement surgery with the Snipe.
現在開始使用“醫狙” 進行二尖瓣置換手術
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -這裡
-Electroscalpel.
-電燒刀
Avoid the lungs after incision.
切開胸膜後，要避開肺部
-Gauze ball. -Right.
-紗布球 -好
Here we go.
開始吧
Dr. Nishizaki expressed zero concern.
西崎教授說完全不必擔心
Please observe.
請安心地看吧
-Tourniquet. -Here.
-止血帶 -這裡
Forceps.
止血鉗
-The Snipe is ready. -I know.
-“醫狙”準備好了 -我知道
MITRAL VALVE - HYPERTROPHY
（二尖瓣，肥大部分）
-Inserting the Snipe. -Keep it down.
-插入“醫狙” -吵死了
Twenty-eight millimeters to the left from the apex.
從心尖左邊28毫米的地方插入
At an 83-degree angle.
以83度的角度往前推
With such ease, Dr. Tokai is incredible.
這麼輕鬆就辦到了，不愧是渡海醫生
The Saeki Method.
佐伯式手術
While carrying my name, it is a medical procedure
以我命名的這個醫療手術
performed on the mitral valve while the heart continues to beat,
是在心臟跳動時所進行的二尖瓣手術
"on beat," as we say.
也就是所謂的自主心跳…
Excuse me.
我先失陪
-Never before has… -What is it?
-這是目前為止… -怎麼了？
Mr. Kusunoki in room 304 has gone into shock. Ask Dr. Saeki what to do.
304房的楠木先生突然休克 請佐伯教授給予指示
Cardiac tamponade…
是心包填塞…
He's giving a speech. He can't give orders.
他正在演講，無法給你們指示
This is Dr. Saeki's patient. Don't let him die no matter what!
這是佐伯教授的患者 無論如何都不能讓他死掉！
What should we do?
我們該怎麼辦？
Looking good. We'll soon approach the hypertrophy.
很不錯，快到肥大的部分了
This is where it gets tough.
難關來了
Amazing. In such a narrow route.
好厲害，這麼窄的路徑
He's reading the heart's movement.
他完全讀懂了心臟的節奏
-Dr. Sera. -Right.
-世良 -是
-Yes? -It's Mr. Kusunoki in room 304.
-喂？ -304房的楠木先生
He's in shock. Cardiac tamponade.
他休克了，是心包填塞
Is there someone who can help? We need assistance!
有沒有人能過來幫忙？
Mr. Kusunoki is having a cardiac tamponade.
楠木先生出現心包填塞
It must be a ruptured aneurysm.
看來是冠狀動脈瘤破裂
-How did you know? -The professor ordered the test.
-你怎麼知道？ -教授不是要他做檢查嗎？
We'll take a coronary angiogram.
做個冠狀動脈血管造影吧
Right…
對耶…
For it to happen now…
沒想到偏偏是現在…
Give me that. We need emergency surgery.
電話給我，病患需要緊急開刀
Dr. Sekikawa can't do it. And Dr. Saeki is out.
關川醫生做不到，佐伯教授也不在
-He won't last 30 minutes. -What should we do?
-他連30分鐘都撐不下去 -我們該怎麼辦？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
No. If we stop now,
不行，現在停下來
we won't be able to insert the Snipe again.
就沒辦法再次插入“醫狙”了
-This is the only route. -But Mr. Kusunoki…
-這是唯一的路徑 -但楠木先生…
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Nekota.
貓田
-Left side? -Got it.
-左邊吧 -知道了
-Mr. Kusunoki, can you hear me? -Dear!
-楠木先生，你聽得到嗎？ -親愛的！
This is bad. He'll die like this.
太糟了，再這樣下去他會死
Doctor!
醫生！
Someone, hurry!
快來人啊！
What are you doing? Continue the operation!
你們在幹嘛？快點繼續手術
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生！
I can't be in two places at once, so I can only save one of them.
我一個人沒辦法同時去兩個地方 所以只能救其中一個人
Who will you save?
你想救誰？
-What? -No…
-什麼？ -應該說
Who will you kill?
你想殺哪一個？
I can't make a decision like that.
我沒辦法做這種決定
If it were me,
換做是我
I would save both.
我兩個都會救
Both?
兩個？
How?
怎麼做？
Tell them to bring him next to us.
叫他們送到隔壁的手術室
-What? -Tell them now!
-什麼？ -快點！
Okay. Bring him to operating room two!
好，帶病患到第二手術室
Okay. Dr. Sekikawa…
好，關川醫生…
Nekota?
貓田小姐？
Operating Room 2 is ready.
第二手術室準備好了
Mr. Kusunoki?
楠木先生？
-Hurry up! -Right!
-快點！ -好
Are you going over there? What will you do with this patient?
你要去那邊？這個患者怎麼辦？
Take over.
你接手
You continue the operation.
你來繼續動手術
I have to continue?
我來做？
What's wrong? Do you plan on just standing there
怎麼了？難道你只打算呆站在那裡
until I get back?
等我回來？
But…
可是…
You know that there's only one route.
你也知道只有一條路徑
If you continue with the right timing, it'll work, right.
只要抓準時機推出去，手術就成功了
Continue with the right timing? You know it's not that easy.
抓準時機推出去？ 你知道那沒那麼簡單
Aren't there any real doctors here?
這裡沒有人是真正的醫生嗎？
No?
沒有？
Fine.
我知道了
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
What are you doing? Dr. Tokai, get back there!
你在做什麼？渡海醫生，快回去！
Do you plan on continuing?
還要繼續嗎？
-These are the surgeon's orders. -But…
-這是主刀醫生的指示 -可是…
The route only opens when the heart beats.
路徑只有在心臟跳動的時候才會打開
I know that!
我知道！
We have to try.
但我們得試試看
Why from the left? Incisions are done in the center.
為什麼從左邊？應該從中間開胸吧？
Move it.
礙事
Opening from the left?
從左邊開胸？
I'll start with the coronary artery aneurysm.
我要先處理破裂的冠狀動脈瘤
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -這裡
Why open up from the left?
為什麼會從左側開胸？
A median sternotomy is standard.
傳統的做法是正中開胸
An incision in the center of the chest.
也就是從胸部的正中間下刀
Why make it harder and go from the left?
為什麼要選擇比較難的左側開胸？
Hey.
喂
Yes?
好的
-Excuse me. -Get that off. You do it.
-失禮了 -拿走，你弄就好
Okay.
好的
-Video. -Okay.
-畫面 -好
It's on.
畫面出來了
-Sternal retractor. -Right.
-開胸器 -這裡
Monitor on.
畫面出來了
It's taking longer than expected, but it's under control.
雖然跟渡海先生比 多花了一點時間，但非常順利
I think we can do this.
我們應該可以成功
We got PSVT!
出現陣發性心律過速！
PSVT in room one!
第一手術室患者出現心律過速
PSVT… Did they hit the muscle?
心律過速，難道是碰到心肌了？
No. It's just arrhythmia. Administer verapamil.
不是，只是心律不整，注射心舒平
Dr. Tokai says to administer verapamil since it's regular arrhythmia.
渡海醫生說只是一般的心律不整 注射心舒平
We've been told to administer verapamil.
他要我們注射心舒平
Two surgeries at once? What is this man capable of?
同時處理兩台手術？ 他到底是什麼樣的人？
Here's the verapamil.
心舒平拿來了
-Hurry! -Right.
-快點！ -好
-Anesthesiologist, hurry.
-麻醉師，快點
Damn it…
可惡
Dr. Takashina…
高階醫生
-Metz. -Here.
-組織剪 -這裡
Aneurysm suture complete.
冠狀動脈瘤縫合完畢
-Already? -Electroscalpel.
-這麼快？ -電燒刀
-Open him up. Raise the bed. -Right.
-胸部打開，床抬高 -是
We'll bypass the aneurysm and stabilize blood flow.
接下來要做冠狀動脈搭橋 恢復血液的流通就好
This is a difficult operation.
這是很困難的手術
What's going on there?
那邊怎麼樣了？
Irregular heartbeat…
心律不整…
If they miss by even one millimeter…
只要有一毫米的誤差
They'll hit the muscle and kill the patient.
碰到心肌就會致死
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Metz.
組織剪
-Bypass complete. -Impossible. You're too fast.
-搭橋完成 -不可能，那太快了
-Thank God.
-這邊搭橋完成 -謝天謝地
-Blood pressure, 72. -What?
-血壓72 -什麼？
It won't stabilize. Why?
血壓沒有回去，為什麼？
Because of the patient's narrow mitral valves.
因為病患原本二尖瓣狹窄的關係嗎？
To save him…
如果要救他…
We'll need the Saeki Method. Dr. Tokai can do it.
就只能用佐伯式手術 渡海醫生辦得到
-Heart-lung machine. -Right!
-準備人工心肺機 -是！
-Blood pump! -Okay!
-血液幫浦！ -好
Room two. Bypass complete.
第二手術室搭橋完成
We'll perform the Saeki Method.
即將進行佐伯式手術
Blood pressure 70-40. Heart rate 110.
血壓70/40，心率110
-Hurry. -Right!
-快點！ -是！
Wait.
等一下
Blood pressure 72. It won't stabilize.
血壓在70左右，沒有回升
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
If we continue like this,
再這樣下去
the patient will surely die.
病患必死無疑
So you plan on just letting him die?
你就打算放任他死掉？
I can't do it.
辦不到的事就是辦不到
I know the limits of my own abilities.
我的能力我自己最清楚
Gown.
手術服
-Dr. Tokai. -Here.
-渡海醫生 -是
How? What about the other operation?
怎麼會？那邊的手術呢？
I'll take over.
換人
I got this one. You finish up over there.
這邊我來，你去那邊收尾
-The Saeki Method? Me? -No way.
-要我做佐伯式？ -怎麼可能？
Dr. Tokai. I've brought it.
渡海醫生，我拿來了
Use the Snipe.
用“醫狙”
The Snipe?
“醫狙”？
I opened that patient up on the left.
我從左邊開胸了
Insert the Snipe from the apex.
可以用“醫狙”從心尖進去
That was your plan from the start?
難道你一開始就想好了？
What is this about?
怎麼回事？
He was planning on using the Snipe from the beginning.
他打從一開始就打算 之後用“醫狙”動手術了
With the standard central incision,
如果從正中間開胸
the apex isn't exposed
就無法露出心尖的部分
and the Snipe can't be inserted.
因此不可能使用“醫狙”
But doing it with such ease…
但他這麼輕而易舉地辦到
What skill!
真是太厲害了
-How were you able to verify it-- -Do it.
-這沒有經過驗證… -做就對了
Surgeon's orders.
這是主刀醫生的命令
Understood.
我知道了
Dr. Takashina…
高階醫生
We'll perform mitral valve surgery with the Snipe.
我們將用“醫狙”進行二尖瓣手術
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir.
-開始吧 -是
-We'll apply stitches to the apex first. -Right.
-先進行心尖部的縫合
-Snipe. -Here.
-“醫狙” -這裡
Inserting the Snipe.
插入“醫狙”
Using the Snipe on both patients…
兩邊的病患都使用“醫狙”
It's in.
插入了
Blood gas analysis results. Here.
這是血液氣體分析結果
Approaching mitral valve.
即將到達二尖瓣
We've made contact.
到達二尖瓣了
Finished.
完成
They did it.
他們辦到了
-It was a success! -Thank you.
-成功了 -謝謝
-Can you apply sutures? -Yes.
-能交給你縫合嗎？ -可以
A once-in-a-lifetime double Snipe surgery.
兩邊同時進行“醫狙”手術 這是再好不過的結果了
That man…
那個人…
has the devil's skills.
果然有著如惡魔般的技術
I see. So it was on Dr. Tokai's orders?
這樣啊，所以是渡海的指示？
And it seems both of them…
看來他們兩個人
used the Snipe, apparently.
都用了“醫狙”
-The Snipe? -Yes.
-“醫狙”？ -對
I see.
這樣啊
Thank you, Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生，謝謝你
-It's nothing. -About my predecessor…
-不用客氣 -前任主編
It appears he has fallen ill
似乎是身體不適
and he won't be in attendance today.
今天不會出席了
He'll be better soon, I'm sure.
我想他應該很快就會康復吧
My son was saved by the Snipe.
“醫狙”救了我兒子
As for the election,
至於理事長選舉
my close relationship with the lobbyists and voting board members
我和幾位有投票權的理事關係很好
will benefit you.
我會替你說話的
That is very encouraging. Please send them our regards.
那我就放心了，請替我向他們打招呼
Until next time.
再見
Well done, Dr. Takashina.
高階，做得好
Now, the real test begins.
真正的勝負現在才要開始
I promise I will complete my paper soon.
我保證會盡快完成論文的
For you, Dr. Nishizaki.
為了西崎教授您
It's almost time.
時間差不多了
Excuse me.
失禮了
Dr. Tokai. Mr. Kusunoki is being released.
渡海醫生，楠木先生要出院了
They're looking for you.
他們在找你
Thank you for everything, Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生，這一切真是太謝謝您了
I'm glad you're feeling better.
您恢復健康真是太好了
I promise to repay you.
我一定會報答您
Thank you, everyone.
謝謝大家
-Please take care. -We will.
-請保重 -好的
Excuse us.
那我們告辭了
Why did they leave through the back door?
他們為什麼從後門離開？
Mr. Hideo Kusunoki.
楠木秀雄先生
He's the former editor-in-chief of the Japan Surgical Journal.
他是《日本外科期刊》的前任主編
The Journal's editors are greatly influenced by him.
他對期刊的編輯們仍有很大的影響力
If the Surgical Association finds out that someone as influential as him
如果外科學會發現 這麼有影響力的楠木先生
didn't go to Dr. Nishizaki for heart surgery, but instead came to me…
沒有選擇西崎教授 而是來我這裡做心臟手術
it would lead to unfairness in the elections.
可能會覺得選舉不太公平
You mean…
難道那時候…
I would save both.
我兩個都會救
The reason Dr. Tokai saved both is…
渡海醫生兩個人都救的原因…
No matter how well-written your paper may be,
不管你的論文寫得多好
whether or not it ends up being published,
能不能被刊登出來
will depend entirely on whose name is written at the end.
完全取決於論文最後寫的是誰的名字
Will it be Dr. Nishizaki?
是西崎教授
Or me?
還是我？
I just realized Dr. Tokai didn't make any demands this time, did he?
我剛發現渡海醫生這次沒提什麼要求
-What? -It's just…
-什麼？ -沒什麼
He usually doesn't help without payment.
要他幫忙，他通常都會先要錢
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Congratulations on a job well done.
前幾天的手術，您辛苦了
You had your hand in not one, but two Snipe surgeries.
您這次特別進行了 兩台使用“醫狙”的手術
Can I ask for your cooperation again?
之後能請您繼續幫忙嗎？
Is he really such a bad guy?
他真的有那麼壞嗎？
Thanks to him, the patients were saved.
多虧有他，兩位病患才能得救
You don't get it. He's the devil.
你不懂，他是惡魔
Excuse me. Dr. Tokai?
打擾了，渡海醫生
I'm here for Mr. Igarashi's reports.
我來拿五十嵐先生的診斷書
Excuse me.
打擾了
Forceps?
止血鉗？
This is…
這是…
If you don't need them anymore, give them to me. Your black forceps.
如果你不需要了 就把你的黑色止血鉗給我
You're no longer needed.
這裡不需要你了
Our biggest problem is the blood transfusion.
最大的問題是輸血
The Snipe exists because of her.
“醫狙”是為了她存在的
I bet everything on this.
我願意為此賭上一切
There's less than a five-percent success rate.
成功率不到百分之五
Is that why Dr. Tokai said no?
所以渡海醫生才會拒絕？
If we fail, we will just remove Dr. Takashina's name.
如果失敗 只要拿掉高階醫生的名字就好
I will succeed for sure.
我一定會成功
You're the only one who can help this patient.
只有你能幫這個病患
Why don't you kill her?
你何不直接殺了她？
You heard what the doctor told me.
你聽到教授跟我說的了
With my current skill, it's impossible!
憑我現在的能力，這是不可能的！
What will you do?
你會怎麼做？
Believe in me.
相信我
Don't believe him.
別相信他
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：林婉婷